-==破烂熊乐园倾情奉献==-
多好的天气啊
Splendid air.
打场猎?
Rough shooting?
或者再钓会鱼?
Perhaps a little fishing.
还有萨塞克斯郡最棒的厨师
And the best cook in the county of Sussex
你说是吗?
wouldn't you say?
福尔摩斯!
Holmes!
还有雷金纳德・马斯格雷夫
And Reginald Musgrave.
他是英国最古老的
Well he is a sign
一个家族的后裔
of one of the oldest families in England.
他是我的大学同学
He was in the same college as myself.
在同学中
He was not generally popular
不太受欢迎
among the undergraduates
但我总认为
but he always seemed to me
他表现出的那种傲慢
that what was set down as pride,
是为了掩饰他的
was really a cover for
天生羞怯的表现
extreme natural diffidence.
每当我想起他那
Indeed I never think of his
苍白 瘦削的脸
pale, lean face
以及头部的姿态
and the poise of his head
脑海里总会浮现灰色的拱道
without associating him with gray archways,
直棂窗
mullioned windows
还有一堆封建古堡的颓垣败瓦
and all the venerable wreckage of a feudal keep.
既然你诸多不满
Well if you feel so uncharitable
为什么还要接受他的邀请?
why didn't you accept his invitation?
想逃离死气沉沉的气氛
To escape my lethargy
还有你对打扫贝克街
and you're constant bullying
那房子的孜孜不倦
to tidy our room in Baker Street.
没有孜孜不倦
Hardly constant.
我打算用整个周末
So I have decided to devote my weekend
来整理我早期的案件
to the collating of some of my early works.
什么早期的案件?
What early works?
在我的传记作家
It was before my biographer
来颂扬我之前的案件
came to glorify me.
你是说你有早期案件的记录?
Do you mean you have records of your work?
不是都是成功的案子
Not all successes.
但也有个别迷人的案子
But some pretty little problems.
塔尔顿凶杀案的记录
Record of the Tarleton murders,
范贝里酒商案
the case of Vamberry, the wine merchant,
俄罗斯老妇历险记
the adventure of the old Russian woman,
畸足人里科里特
a full account of
和他那可恶妻子
Ricoletti with the clubfoot,
案件的详细记录
and his abominable wife
还有铝制拐杖案
and the singular affair of the aluminum crutch.
铝制拐杖?
Aluminum crutch?
那东西有点过分讲究
Now that was something a little recherché?
我希望我也有这些案子的笔记
I wish I had notes of these cases.
想得倒美
Yes my boy.
随房主参观
Well you may hold my interest for a few hours
古董历史长廊
while you potter with our host
也许能让我感兴趣个几个小时
through the antiquities of a by gone age.
房子能让你感兴趣吧?
Surely the house interests you?
那房子冷极了 华生!
The house is freezing Watson!
那是历史
It's history.
房子里的人
The people in there.
我记得你说过
On your previous visit
你上次拜访时
I remember you telling me
和一名男管家有许多
that you endured some lively conversations
精彩的对话
with a butler.
他叫布兰斯顿吗?
What's his name Brunston?
啊 布兰斯顿
Oh Brunton.
一名当起了管家的年轻教师
A young schoolteacher out of place.
他是不是...是不是会几国语言?
Did he not... did he not speak several languages?
是的 还会弹奏几乎所有乐器
Yes, he played nearly every musical instrument.
一位远比其主人
A man of considerably
要聪明的男士
more intellectual ability than his master.
华生 我们要得体一点
Watson we must behave ourselves.
布兰斯顿
Awe, Brunton.
福尔摩斯先生 很高兴能再次见到你
Mr. Holmes, a pleasure to see you again.
我的朋友兼同事 华生医生
My friend and colleague, Doctor Watson.
欢迎来到赫尔斯通 先生
Welcome to Hurlstone, sir.
马斯格雷夫
Musgrave,
我的朋友兼同事 华生医生
my friend and colleague, Doctor Watson.
见到你们真高兴 久别了
So glad, it's a long time.
是啊
Yeah.
这段时间过得怎样?
How is all gone with you?
忙啊 忙啊
Oh busy, busy.
我父亲去世了
My father died.
我得接手管理这座庄园
I've had the estates to manage.
而我现在亦是本区
And as I am now a member of parliament
议会的一员
the district as well.
而你...似乎
But you... you I have noticed
还在将你在大学时让人吃惊的
are still turning to practical end of powers
那套本事运用到现实生活中
with which you used to amaze us at college.
是的 我还是靠脑子为生
Yes, I'm still living by wits
女主人呢?
and how is the dear wife?
我没结婚呢 福尔摩斯
I'm not married Holmes.
明智
How wise.
窗户的年代可追朔至1596年
And the windows date from 1596.
这座庄园被认为是
The manor is thought to be
全国尚有人居住的最古老的庄园
the oldest inhabited building in the country.
我知道北方也有姓马斯格雷夫的
I once knew some northern Musgrave's.
他们的确来自北方
They did come from the north originally.
家族中的一支庶系分支
A cadet branch of the family
脱离了北方的马斯格雷夫家族
broke away from the northern Musgrave's
于十七世纪初来到了
and came to West Sussex
北萨塞克斯
in the early seventeenth century.
福尔摩斯?
Holmes?
再来点白兰地吗 先生?
More brandy sir?
不了 布兰斯顿
No, Brunton.
这就是事情的经过 兰德尔
That's how the story goes, Randall,
我可以保证
and I can vouch for it.
但是委任状在这
But the commission is over here,
由鲁珀特王子签发的
signed by Prince Rupert.
从我的祖先拉夫・马斯格雷夫流传下来的
It's from my ancestor the Ralph Musgrave.
在边山拥有一支骑兵连
Yes, enjoy is cavalry troop at Edge Hill.
鲁珀特的封印章和委任书 福尔摩斯
Rupert's seal and commissioned Holmes.
太让人吃惊了
Astonishing.
这是那天穿的靴子
It's one of the boots worn that day.
恕我无礼 先生
If I may be so bold sir.
嗯?
Huh?
这对靴子是他哥哥穿的
The boot was worn by his brother,
罗兰・马斯格雷夫先生
Sir Roland Musgrave.
实际上
That was indeed,
我的管家曾是一名教师
my butler was once a schoolmaster,
他的学识以及对我家族史的了解
I must bow to his scholarship over mine
都远在我之上
and matters of my own family's history.
不 不 不 不用了
No, no, no never mind
你可以离开了
you may leave us now.
对了 布兰斯顿
Yeah but Brunton
瑞秋今晚去哪了?
where is Rachel tonight?
她发低烧
She has a slightest temperature.
我让她回房间了
I told her to go to her room.
晚安 先生们
Good night, gentlemen.
福尔摩斯...福尔摩斯跟我说过
Holmes... Holmes has told me
布兰斯顿的奇思妙想
of Brunton's extraordinary idea.
我记得上一次拜访的时候
But I remember on my last visit
他花了几个小时
where he spent several hours
用法语给我讲述
explaining to me in French
短笛的起源
the origins of the piccolo.
他满足于这个职位如此之久
It is wonderful that he should be satisfied
实在太让人惊讶了
for so long with such a position
我想...
but I suppose...
我想他过得太安逸了
I suppose he's been comfortable
也就不思进取了
and lacked the energy to make a change.
的确如此
Oh yes, indeed.
赫尔斯通的男管家
The butler of Hurlstone.
总让来访的宾客
It's always a thing that is remembered
印象深刻
by all who visit us.
亲爱的马斯格雷夫
Oh dear Musgrave,
但是 这个完人有一个缺点
However, this paragon does have one fault,
有点唐璜(玩弄女性的荒淫贵族)的风格
a bit of a Don Juan.
在安静的乡村扮演这样的角色
Well it's not a difficult part to play
可没有难度
in quiet country district.
他结婚的时候 尚算检点
When he was married he was all right,
但成了鳏夫以后
but since he's become a widower
就麻烦不断了
we've had no end of trouble with him.
几个月前
I mean, a few months ago
他终于有安定下来的希望了
we were in hopes he was about to settle down again.
他和瑞秋・豪威尔订婚了
He became engaged to Rachel Howells,
我的第二任女仆
my second housemaid
但他把她抛弃了
but he has thrown her over.
和珍妮・特雷杰丽丝
Taken up with Janet Tregallis,
猎场看守人的女儿好上了
my gamekeeper's daughter.
瑞秋是个好女孩
Rachel is a very good girl,
但她有着威尔士人的那种易激动的脾气
but she is of an excitable Welsh temperament.
现在她像个鬼魂似的到处游荡
Now she wonders around like a black-eyed shadow,
害得上上下下都闷闷不乐
thoroughly unsettling the household.
瑞秋?
Rachel?
早上好 福尔摩斯
Good morning, Holmes,
雷金纳德先生
Sir Reginald.
谢谢
Thank you.
布兰斯顿去哪了?
Where's Brunton this morning?
没事 没事
It's all right, it's all right.
没事
Nothing.
没事了
It's all right.
她要晕过去了 华生
The girl is fainting, Watson.
年轻的女士
My dear young woman,
你不该干活
you should not be at work
而该待在床上
you should be in bed.
你可以请假 瑞秋
You may leave your duties, Rachel.
感觉好些了再回来
Come back when you're feeling stronger.
我很好 先生
I am strong enough, sir.
这由我说得算
I'll be the judge of that.
你得回房间
You must go to your room.
不
No.
躺下
Lie down.
回房的时候告诉布兰斯顿
And on your way tell Brunton
我想见他
that I wish to see him.
管家走了
The butler is gone.
走了?
Gone?
走去哪?
Gone where?
他走了
He's gone.
他现在不在房间
He's not in his room now.
没有人见到他
No one's seen him.
没错 没错 他走了
Oh, yes, yes, he's gone.
他走了
He's gone.
没事了
It's all right.
轻轻地 轻点
Gently.Gentle.
放轻松 瑞秋
Gently Rachel.
没事了
It's all right.
放轻松 瑞秋 放轻松
Gently, Rachel, gently.
轻点
Gentle.
床没有睡过的痕迹
The bed's not been slept in.
你找过房子的其他地方么?
Have you searched the house?
从顶楼到地窖都找过了
From cellar to garret.
那女孩说得没错 没有他的踪影
The girl's right there's no trace of him.
他走了
He's gone.
不知道他怎么出去的
Do not see how the man could have left.
窗户和门都锁着
I mean the windows and door are all fastened.
为什么一个人大半夜出走
What man goes away in the middle of the night
却什么都没带?
and leaves all his possessions behind?
没带钱 怀表?
And money, watch?
我已经让那女孩
Well I've given the girl
平复下来了
something to calm her down
而且自作主张
and I've taken the liberty
请了位本地护士
to sending for a local nurse.
她现在精神极度紧张
She's in a most unusual nervous state.
她绝对不适宜
And she should, on no account,
独自呆着
be left alone for a while.
她就是和布兰斯顿订婚的女孩?
This is the girl who was engaged to Brunton?
瑞秋・豪威尔 是的 是的
Rachel Howells, yes, yes.
有着威尔士人脾气的女孩
Girl with a fine Welsh temper.
华生
Oh Watson.
各位 我无意让如此琐碎的
Look gentlemen I had no intention of this
家庭小事
small domestic incident
破坏你们的周末
should ruin your weekend.
我提议依计划去打猎
I propose we continue our plans for a shoot
希望回来的时候
and we'll return hopefully
能有答案
to some simple explanation.
福尔摩斯?
Holmes?
干的好 华生
Well done, Watson.
福尔摩斯?
Holmes?
正如我跟华生所说
As I was telling Watson,
昨晚发生了一些事情
something happened last night,
也许能为这件事提供点线索
which may throw some light on this matter.
这么说很丢脸 但...
This is very embarrassing but I...
我需要你的建议
I find I need your advice.
晚饭后不明智地喝了杯咖啡
I couldn't sleep after foolishly taking
导致我睡不着
that cup of Coffee after dinner
大约两点的时候 我放弃了尝试
and about two o'clock I gave up the struggle.
去楼下图书馆
I came downstairs to fetch a novel I'm reading,
拿我在读的一本小说
which I'd left in the library.
你能想象我有多惊讶
Well you can imagine my surprise
当我看到门开着
when I saw a glimmer of light
里面透出灯光
coming from the open door.
我记得我们离开前
I'd remembered I had extinguished the lamp
已经熄了灯关了门
and closed the door when we retired.
自然而然我就想到盗窃
Naturally my first thought was burglars.
这就是你回报我的信任的方式
So this is how you repay my trust,
窥探我的家族资料?
prying into my family documents?
明天马上离职
You will leave my service tomorrow.
马斯格雷夫先生
Mr. Musgrave, sir,
我不想带着耻辱离开
I can't be a disgrace.
我一直都为自己的地位自豪
I've always been proud about my station in life,
耻辱会让我生不如死
and disgrace would kill me.
如果你把我逼上绝路
My blood will be on your head sir,
你的手上就会沾满我的鲜血
it will indeed if you drive me to despair.
什么?
What?
如果我不能保住工作
If you cannot keep me after this,
那看在上帝的份上
then for God sake
让我向你辞职
let me give you notice
在一个月内离开
and leave in a month
当作是我自己的意愿
as of my own free will.
一个月太长了
A month is too long.
我可以忍受 马斯格雷夫先生
I could stand that, Mr. Musgrave,
只要不是当着
but not to be cast out
我认识的人面前被赶走
before all the folk I know so well.
你不配这种照顾 布兰斯顿
You don't deserve consideration, Brunton.
你已经声名狼藉了
Your conduct has been infamous.
然尔 我无意让你
However, I've no wish
当众受辱
to bring public disgrace upon you.
一个星期内自行离开
You take yourself away in a week,
无论你用什么理由
and you give whatever reason you like.
一个星期 先生?
A week, sir?
只有一个星期?
Only a week?
两周 起码两周
A fortnight-say at least a fortnight!
不 一个星期!
No a week!
你要意识到
And you may consider yourself
这已经是宽大处理了
to have been very leniently dealt with.
奇怪之处在于
But what is strange
他似乎非常紧张能否久留
is that he seemed most anxious to stay.
之后的事情就显而易见了
Well it's quite plain to me what happened.
他回到房间
He went back to his room,
深思熟虑
thought it over,
决定立刻消失
decided to stage his disappearance,
非常明智
there and then cleverly.
也许在新女朋友的帮助下
Possibly with the help of his new woman friend.
珍妮?
Janet?
不 不 不
No, no, no,
她和她父亲
She lives with her father
住在湖对岸
on the other side of the lake
而且 我怀疑她是否有
and besides I doubt if she'd have
帮助他的本事
the wit to help him.
这张纸
This piece of paper
布兰斯顿认为值得
which Brunton thought worth his while to consult,
冒失去工作的危险一读
even at the risk of the losing his job?
什么都不是
Well it's nothing.
什么重要的信息也没有
It's nothing of any importance at all.
尽管如此
Nevertheless.
这只是份古老奇怪的礼典抄件
It's simply a copy of the singular old observance
叫做马斯格雷夫礼典
called the Musgrave Ritual.
我的家族对此毫不陌生
Seldom peculiar to our family,
每个马斯格雷夫家族成员
which each Musgrave has to go through
成年时都需要接受
when he's coming of age.
是份奇怪的教义问答集
This is a strange catechism.
没有日期 但却使用
Undated but written in the style
十七世纪中叶的风格拼写
of the middle of the seventeenth century.
你和华生能
Would you and Watson be good enough
为我读一下吗?
to read it out to me?
医生 我已经烂熟于心了
Oh Doctor, I know it by heart.
它是谁的?
Whose was it?
那个离开的人
His who is gone.
谁应拥有它?
Who shall have it?
那个将到来的人
He who will come.
太阳于何处?
Where was the sun?
橡树之上
Over the oak.
影子于何处?
Where was the shadow?
榆树之下
Under the elm.
如何测量?
How was it stepped?
向西八步乘八步
West eight by eight,
向南七步乘七步
south seven by seven,
向西六步乘六步
west six by six,
向南五步乘五步 两步乘两步
south five by five and two by two,
于此下方
and so under.
用何物换取?
What shall we give for it?
倾吾所有
All that is ours.
为何换取?
Why should we give it?
因为守信
For the sake of the trust.
这是个寻宝迷题
Why, it's a treasure hunt.
不 不 我记得小时候
Oh no, no, I remember as children
我们总想破解它
we often tried to solve it.
总是徒劳无功
It leads nowhere.
布兰斯顿以前看过这份东西吗?
Could Brunston have seen this before last night?
有可能
Well it's possible.
我们从不费心藏起来
We took no pains to hide it
但他要来有什么用呢?
but what could he want with it?
明显是想加深记忆
Obviously he was refreshing his memory.
你说你进去时
You say that he had some map or chart,
他正把某些地图或图表
which he was thrust back into his pocket
往口袋里塞?
the moment you appeared?
似乎是的
That's what it looked like.
好吧
Yes.
我们必须再次研究这份礼典
We must reexamine this ritual.
这些数据明显是指向
The measurements obviously refer
某一特定地点
to some exact spot
礼典的其余部分没有明确指明
to which the rest of the document eludes.
有两个提示?
You are given two guides?
是的 榆树和橡树
Yes, an elm and an oak.
先生们 橡树中有棵树王
And gentlemen, there is a patriarch among oaks.
绝对是庄园内最古老的橡树
Certainly the oldest oak on the estate.
这棵树肯定在诺曼底人
This tree must have been here
征服英国时就存在了
in the time of the Norman Conquest.
非常可能
In all probability
但我告诉你
but I tell you
这不可能是礼典中的橡树 福尔摩斯
it can't be the oak referred to, Holmes.
历代的马斯格雷夫
Generations of Musgrave's
都尝试破解这礼典
have attempted to solve it.
有一半的地都被挖过
They've dug up half this field.
你说得对 马斯格雷夫
You are right, Musgrave,
这不是礼典中的橡树
this is not the oak referred to in the ritual.
这附近还有没有
Are there any other large oaks
别的大橡树?
in the immediate vicinity?
房子一英里内没有
Not within a mile of the house.
太阳于何处?
Where was the sun?
橡树之上
Over the oak.
你今天什么也做不了
You can make nothing of it today, old man,
天气变了
the weather's turned.
理查德先生      早上好
Sir Richard.        Good morning.
这有八英尺深
It's eight foot deep here.
可怜的疯女孩
Poor demented girl.
还有希望
We must live and hope, old man.
尸体还没找到呢
There's been no body found yet.
一无所获 先生
Nothing so far sir.
我们都快捞遍了
We've just about covered all of it.
这里有发现!
We found something!
里面有什么?
What does it contain?
毫无价值的东西
Nothing of value.
任何人任何时候能抛这么个袋子
It could have been thrown in by anyone at anytime.
是最近扔的 否则水早就把它腐蚀了
No recently or the water would have rotted the bag.
女仆昨晚抛的
The maid last night.
这能表明她来过湖边
Well it would explain her journey to the mere
但接着又去哪了呢?
but then where did she go?
这里啥都没有 福尔摩斯
There's nothing here, Holmes.
只是一堆
It's just a mass of,
生锈褪色的金属和鹅卵石
rusted and discolored metal and some pebbles.
而布兰斯顿和瑞秋
And where is Brunton
在哪里?
or Rachel?
为什么有人会费神
Why should anybody bother
把这些东西扔进湖里?
to throw this into the lake?
我确信
I am convinced
没有三个谜团
that there are not three mysteries here,
只有一个
but only one,
只要解开一个
and the solution of one
就能顺藤摸瓜 解决其余的谜团
may prove the solutions to the others.
布兰斯顿肯定在这里发现什么
Apparently Brunton saw something in this,
而你未能发现 马斯格雷夫
which escaped your forbears, Musgrave,
他希望能从中得利
from which he expected some personal advantage.
如果我没推测错
If I can read it right
我手中掌握着
I hold in my hand the clue
关于管家布兰斯顿和女仆瑞秋
to the truth concerning both the butler Brunton
事情真相的线索
and the maid Howells.
太阳于何处? 橡树之上
Wherever is the sun over the oak?
影子于何处? 榆树之下
Where was the shadow on the elm?
这就是榆树生长的位置?
So this is where it grew?
是的
Yes.
我想已经不可能告诉我
I suppose it's impossible
树的高度了吧?
to tell me how high it was?
我立马就能告诉你
I can give you that at once.
六十四英尺
It was sixty-four feet.
我以前的家庭教师
It's my old tutor;
教我学三角学(研究三角形边和角间关系的学科)
he used to give me lessons in trigonometry.
我小时候就知道
When I was a lad I used to know
庄园内每棵树
the height of every tree
每座建筑的高度了
and building on this estate.
我很感激你的家庭教师
I am grateful to your tutor.
布兰斯顿曾经在这个草坪
Tell me did Brunton ever ask you such a question
问过同样的问题吗?
here on this lawn?
你让我想起来了
Now that you call it to my mind.
布兰斯顿?
Brunton?
你在这做什么呢?
What are you doing here?
享受美好的夜晚 先生
Enjoying the evening, sir.
这是我的私人草坪
This is my private lawn.
请原谅我请教一个问题
You pardon me for asking sir,
曾经在这里的那棵
the elm that once stood here,
被雷击中的榆树
that was struck by lightning,
你已经不记得有多高了
you wouldn't remember the height of it
是吗 先生?
would you sir?
你为什么想知道这个呢?
Well why should you want to know that?
我和特雷杰丽丝先生在争论呢
Well I'm arguing with Mr. Tregallis about it.
我说是五十英尺高 他说不止
I say it was fifty feet, he put it higher.
我们打了个小赌
We have a small wager on it.
那你得输了 布兰斯顿
Oh, well you've lost your wager, Brunton.
是六十四英尺高
It was sixty-four feet.
是吗?
Awe, was it?
我还是大方点
I shall just have to be a good sport
愿赌服输吧
and pay up then.
谢谢 先生
Thank you sir.
福尔摩斯?
Holmes?
没错 华生
Huh?
我的天啊!
Oh good lord!
我们现在必须找到
Now we must find where
当太阳偏离橡树时
the shadow of the elm would have fallen
榆树的影子会落到哪里
when the sun is just clear of that oak.
那很有难度 福尔摩斯
Well that'll be difficult, Holmes,
因为榆树已经没了
since the elm's no longer there.
来吧 华生
Oh now come, Watson.
如果布兰斯顿能做到 我们也能
If Brunton can do it then so can we.
答案就在三角学中
The answer lies in trigonometry.
马斯格雷夫 我需要庄园里的
Musgrave I need all the fishing rods
所有鱼竿
that you have in the hall.
福尔摩斯?
Holmes?
是的
Yes.
我...我不太明白
I... I don't quite follow this.
太好了!
Awe splendid!
马斯格雷夫?
Musgrave?
庄园里所有的鱼竿
Every rod in the house.
谢谢
Thank you.
请把尺子给我 华生
Measuring stick please, Watson.
请帮我拿着好吗 马斯格雷夫?
Would you hold that for me, Musgrave please?
还有那个?
And that?
现在将绳子一端
Now will you take the last yard of the string
绑在鱼竿底部 华生
and tie it to the base of the fishing rod, Watson?
好的
Yes.
完成以后
And when you've done that
带着礼典
would you bring the Ritual
来草坪找我
and join me on the lawn?
请量一下那个影子好吗 华生?
Would you measure that shadow, please Watson?
九英尺
Nine feet.
这一来就很容易计算了
So the calculation is now a simple one.
如果鱼竿是六英尺
If a fishing rod of six feet
投下个影子是九英尺
throws a shadow of nine feet
榆树高六十四英尺
then a tree of sixty-four feet
那影子是?
would throw one of?
九十八
Ninety-eight.
九十六
Ninety-six.
没错
Yes of course.
两者肯定在
And the line of one of course
同一直线上
would be the line of the other.
华生 看!
Watson look!
距离我的记号两英寸
Two inches from mine.
布兰斯顿作的记号
A mark made by Brunton.
把步数念给我听
Now read out the steps.
向西八步乘八步
West eight by eight.
六十四步
Sixty-four.
向南七步乘七步
Then south seven by seven.
四十九步
Forty-nine.
向西
West.
六步乘六步
Six by six.
三十六步 然后
Thirty-six and
向南五步乘五步
South Five by five.
然后呢?
And?
两步乘两步
Two by Two.
一 二 三 四
One, two, three, four.
不可能
I don't believe it.
你计算有误
Some mistake in your calculations.
不可能
That's impossible.
布兰斯顿还没来过这
Brunton hasn't been here.
两步乘两步 于此下方
Two by two and so under.
这些石头很多年没有动过了
These stones haven't been moved in many a long year.
于此下方
And under.
福尔摩斯
Holmes.
你忘记了"于此下方"
You've forgotten the 'and under.'
这里有地窖么?
Is there a cellar under here?
有 年代和房子一样老
As old as the house.
这里原本遍地都是木材
There's been wood all over the floor.
那是布兰斯顿的围巾
That's Brunton's muffler.
我确定
I'd swear to it.
华生!
Watson!
巡官 这是我的一位朋友
Inspector, this is a friend of mine,
华生医生
Doctor Watson.
巡官
Inspector,
我在法医学方面有些许经验
I have some experience in forensic pathology.
这名男子已经死亡两天了
The man has been dead for two days.
窒息死亡
Cause of death suffocation.
没有伤口或瘀伤 先生?
No wound or bruise on this person, sir?
没有
None.
意外 是吗?
Accident hey?
毫无疑问
Oh there's no doubt about it.
他肯定一个人在那里
He must have been down there alone
石板就盖上了 可怜的人
and the flagstone just fell shut on him, poor fellow.
雷金纳德先生
Sir Reginald,
据说您的管家所在的地下室
I'm told that your butler was down in the cellar
已经废弃不用了
in an unused part of the house.
他在那里做什么 先生?
What was his business there sir?
管家的工作
A butler's duties
是多样且多变的 巡官
are many and varied, Inspector.
我无法回答那个问题
I can't possibly answer that question.
在那个地方 没有人能听见
Well no one would have heard his cries for help
他的呼救声
in that part of the house,
那便是关键 巡官
that is the point surely, Inspector.
特雷杰丽丝
Tregallis.
瑞秋!
Rachel!
是她干的!
She done it!
她把他给杀了!
She killed him!
所以逃跑了!
That's why she ran away!
特雷杰丽丝!
Tregallis!
瑞秋?
Rachel?
没什么
It's nothing.
仆人们伤心这很正常
The servants are naturally upset.
瑞秋是谁?
Well who is this Rachel?
我的女仆之一
One of my housemaids.
她和布兰斯顿订婚了
She was engaged to Brunton.
请把他盖上
Do please cover him up.
有一天晚上他失踪了
One evening he disappeared.
她就病恹恹然后离开了
She became ill and left.
我想见见她
Well I shall want to see her.
还有刚刚那位年轻女士
I shall want to see that young woman also.
巡佐
Sergeant.
把他抬走
All right take him away
医生 请
Doctor please.
当地的巡官 福尔摩斯
The local inspector Holmes.
如果你能找到一个解释
If you could find a plausible explanation
能避免家丑外扬...
to avoid publicity in this retched...
我得承认
I must confess
迄今为止 我对自己的调查
that so far I am disappointed
非常失望
in my investigation.
我一度认为
I had reckoned upon solving the matter
只要来到礼典所指的地方
when once I'd find the place
就能解开迷题
referred to in the Ritual
但现在我身在此地
but now that I'm here
仍然无法得知
I'm as far as ever
你家族如此精心埋藏的
from knowing where it was your family concealed
究竟是什么
with such an elaborate precautions.
但你解决了布兰斯顿的迷题
But you've solved my mystery of Brunton.
究竟是怎样?
But how?
他为什么会死
How did his fate come upon him
以及失踪的女士
and what part has been played
在这其中又扮演了什么角色?
by the woman whose disappeared?
我要解释一下福尔摩斯的破案方式
I should explain Holmes methods in such cases.
他...他在估量对方的智慧后
He... he puts himself in the man's place
把自己代入对方的角色
having first gauged his intelligence
然后他...
and then he...
会想象假如是他
he tries to imagine how he himself
在同样的情况下
would have proceeded
会如何处理
in similar circumstances.
这个案件中
In this case
布兰斯顿绝顶聪明
Brunton's intelligence is first rate.
因此不必担心
So you see it is unnecessary
他观察问题会出现"个人观察容许误差"
to make allowance for the personal equation.
这是天文学家的说法
As the astronomers have dubbed it.
他知道有东西被藏起来了
He knows something is concealed.
他发现了地点
He has spotted the place.
他发现靠一个人的力量
He has found the stone is too heavy
难以拉动石板
for a man to move unaided.
他该怎么办呢?
So what does he do?
找外人帮忙
Help from outside.
没有人可以信任
No one to trust.
找内部的人帮忙? 找谁呢?
Help from inside but who?
瑞秋
Rachel.
她还爱着他
She still loves him.
从她的眼里就能看出来
He sees it in her eyes.
我是来道歉的 亲爱的
I'm here to say I'm sorry my love.
我是个愚蠢的人
I'm a foolish man.
我配不上你
I don't deserve you.
你配不上
You don't.
原谅我 瑞秋
Forgive me Rachel.
为什么?
Why?
没有别的人能拥有我的心
There's no one else for me.
从没有过 你知道的
No one ever has been, you know that.
这个房子在吞噬你的灵魂
It's this house it eats into your soul.
让我带你离开
Let me take you away from here.
重新开始
We'll start afresh.
你的承诺
Your promises.
哦 理查德 你毫无顾忌和他人发生关系
Oh Richard, you make love so freely.
你从未爱过我
You never loved me.
你错了
Oh you're wrong.
我既爱你的美貌 也爱你的内心
I love you for your beauty and your spirit.
我们是天造地设的一对
We're a perfect match.
我的头脑加上你的心灵
With my brains and your heart
自由在呼唤我们
what do we want with service to others
为什么还要为他人服务呢? 亲爱的
when a world is out there calling us, my love?
身无分文怎么生存?
And how do we get out there with no money?
我们会有钱的
We'll have all the money we need.
我在这所房子里找到了
I found something in this house
所有地主都找不到的东西
all them country squires have missed.
而我找到了 我们可以离开了
Now I've found it and we're ready to go.
和你一起离开
But not without you,
没了你我无法生存
I couldn't live without you.
我要做你的丈夫 瑞秋
I'm to be your husband, Rachel.
什么钱?
What money?
你找到什么了?
What have you found?
跟我来
Come with me.
穿上衣服 我带你去
Put on your gown, I'll show you.
轻点
Softly now.
就在这 在石板下面
There it is, under that stone.
只需把石板拉起
All we have to do is lift it.
那块木头
Now there's some wood.
我拉起来的时候你把它塞进去
Now when I lift this you wedge it.
快点 女人 按我说的做!
Come on woman, do as I tell you!
准备好了吗?
Ready?
再加一块
And another one.
再来一块
And that one over there.
这块木头上有轻微的凹痕
There is a slight indentation on this log.
这块也是
And on this.
由石板的重量造成的
Caused by the weight of the stone.
对女士来说是个重活
Heavy work for a woman.
而这个 我认为
And this, I think,
作为最后的支撑
has been used finally as a support.
那就是我们的宝贝
There's our treasure.
那箱子已经在这200多年了
That box is laying there for two centuries or more.
你要偷了它吗?
Will you steal it?
没人知其存在的东西 怎么偷?
How can you steal what nobody knows exists?
那你是怎么知道的?
Well how did you know then?
靠智慧 姑娘
Brains my girl.
历史和数学
History and mathematics.
来 帮我举着灯
Here, hold the light for me.
把灯举近点
Bring the light closer.
赚大钱!
Make a fortune!
是啊 真有赚头啊
Oh yes, that's a fine profit.
安静点
Be quiet.
这里肯定有点价值的
There must be some value in it.
你真聪明啊!
Oh how clever are you!
应该叫自负
A pride more like.
比自己的主人博学!
Known better than your masters!
安静点 女人
Quiet woman.
我知道你所谓的聪明
I know your cleverness.
丈夫 你只想利用我!
Husband, you just needed me to help you!
如果真有什么财宝
If it had been treasure
你早就把我甩得远远的了!
you'd of been over the way without me!
你会带着她走!
You would have gone with her!
你是个白痴
You're a fool if you believe that.
拿着
Here take this.
帮我上去
Now help me out of here.
瑞秋!
Rachel!
我亲爱的 找人帮忙
My love, get help.
我呼吸不了
I can't breath.
去找福尔摩斯先生 快
Get Mr. Holmes, quickly.
求你了 亲爱的
Please, my love.
瑞秋!
Rachel!
上帝啊 救救我
Oh God, help me.
瑞秋!
Rachel!
救命!
Help!
瑞秋!
Rachel!
救救我!
Help me!
瑞秋!
Rachel!
瑞秋 救救我!
Rachel, help me!
那就能解释她第二天早餐时
That will explain her blanched face
苍白的脸
and her fevered brain
和低烧了
at breakfast the next morning.
只有些菌类植物
Nothing but fungi.
箱子里有什么 福尔摩斯?
But what was in the box, Holmes?
查理一世国王
Sir Charles the First.
也许能找到查理一世的其他物品
We may find something else of Charles the First.
湖里钓上来的袋子
The bag that was fished from the mere.
先生们 看
Gentlemen, look.
宝石
It's a jewel.
传家宝
A family heirloom.
很可能
Well it's possible.
你的祖先拉夫・马斯格雷夫
You're ancestor, Sir Ralph Musgrave,
是位杰出的保皇党党员吗?
was he a prominent cavalier?
是的
Oh yes indeed.
是的 共和国时期(克伦威尔为首的清教徒建立)
Yes he was close to Charles the Second
他与被放逐的查理二世十分亲密
in his wanderings during the Commonwealth.
这构成我们所需信息的
Then I think that should give us
最后一环
the last link that we wanted.
先生们 你们必须知道
Gentlemen, you must bear mind
当皇室成员被流放时
when the royal party were driven into exile
多会将其
they probably left
许多珍贵的财物
many of their most precious possessions
埋藏起来
buried behind them
以备在和平时期
with the intention of returning for them
他们回归故土时使用
in a more peaceful time.
黄金 马斯格雷夫
Gold, Musgrave.
华生 你手中的碎片
Watson I believe you have in your hand a relic,
不仅其本身价值很高
which is not only of great intrinsic value,
其历史价值亦不相伯仲
but also great importance as a historical curiosity.
这是什么?
Well what is it?
这是一块碎片
Nothing less than a fragment
属于古英格兰国王皇冠的一部分
of the ancient crown of the kings of England.
皇冠!
The crown!
不 不 福尔摩斯
Oh no, no, Holmes.
这太不切实际了
It's too amiable.
回想一下礼典
Now consider the ritual.
是怎么说的?
How does it run?
它是谁的?
Whose was it?
那个离开的人
His who is gone.
那是指被处死的查理一世
That was the execution of Charles.
接着是"谁应拥有它?"
And then who shall have it?
那个将到来的人
He who will come.
这是指查理二世
That was Charles the Second,
其归来已经预见到了
whose advent was already foreseen.
我想 毫无疑问 先生们
There can, I think, be no doubt, gentlemen,
这个破碎得不成型的皇冠
that this battered and shapeless diadem
曾经属于斯图亚特王朝
once encircle the brows of the royal Stuart's.
那怎么会出现在我家?
But how came it into my family?
当查理一世被处决时
When Charles the First was executed
皇冠被抢走了
the crown was seized.
摔成碎片
Broken into pieces
高价卖出
and sold for a thousand guineas.
至此下落不明
Since then there has been no trace of it,
直至现在
until now.
为什么查理二世回来时不拿走?
But why did Charles not get it back on his return?
这个问题 也许永远不会有答案
That is a question, which may never be answered.
你的祖先去世时 由于疏忽
When you ancestor died by some oversight,
将这个指引留给其子孙
he left this guide to his descendent
而没对其内容做任何解释
without ever explaining the meaning of it.
世代相传
Father to son.
直至落入一名男子手中
Until at last it came within reach
将谜团解开
of a man who tore it's secret out of it
并丧命于这场冒险中
and lost his life in the venture.
瑞秋!
Rachel!
木棍真的是自行滑落吗
Was it chance that the wood slipped
她的罪仅在于没有呼救吗?
was she only guilty of silence?
她有着容易激动的凯尔特人脾性
She had a passionate, Celtic soul.
那个男人负了他
The man had wronged her.
她可以决定其生死
She had it in her power.
是为了复仇
Might it rather been vengeance
而将石板盖上吗?
that sent the stone crashing?
用她的双手把木棍抽走
Her hand that dashed it away.
她现在在哪里呢?
Now what has become of her?
可能已经带着她的秘密
Very probably she's far away from Hurlstone now
远走高飞了
and carries her secret with her.
-==http://www.ragbear.com==-